A Guide to the 1907 Jamestown Exposition, St. Paul's Episcopal Church, 1907-1908
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
1907 Jamestown Exposition, St. Paul's Episcopal Church 1907-1908
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
89
1 Hollinger Document Case
Saint Paul's Episcopal Church
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
A gift from St. Paul's Episcopal Church on May 14, 2007.
Biographical Information
The 1907 Jamestown Exposition was held to commemorate the 300th anniversary of the establishment of Jamestown. Jamestown was the first permanent English settlement in the United States. The Exposition lasted from April 26 to December 1, 1907 and was held in Norfolk, Virginia. The Episcopal Church exhibited in the 1907 Exposition was the first Protestant Episcopal Church in America, guiding the people in building the society and maintaining order. The Committee on Arrangements of the Jamestown Exposition in conjunction with other churches and members of the community helped to establish and create this Tercentennial Celebration in 1907. The committee, on whom this collection is focused, gathered support, information, artifacts, and photographs all in the effort to hold an exposition honoring the first settlement in the United States. The Chairmen of this committee were Reverend Alfred Magill Randolph and Reverend Corbin Braxton Bryan.
Scope and Content
The papers of the 1907 Jamestown Exposition date from January 1907 to January 1908. The collection includes paperwork related to the Jamestown Exposition and the Episcopal Church. The collection contains historical information of the Episcopal Church at the 1907 Jamestown Exposition. Materials were donated by Saint Paul's Episcopal Church in Norfolk, VA. Materials consists of information reflecting the planning of the exhibit, the collecting of documents and artifacts, and correspondence between members of the Exposition committee and other churches regarding the exhibit. The collection is broken down into two series: I: Business; and II: Correspondence.
Arrangement
The collection is broken down into two series: I: Business; and II: Correspondence.
Index Terms
Jamestown Ter-centennial Exposition (1907); Letters (correspondence); Postcards; Minutes
Contents List
- Business 1907
  This series contains information about meeting minutes of the planning committee, bills, and payments from shipping orders placed throughout the entire year of 1907. The paperwork shows correspondence between church members about what items were requested and shipped for display in the Jamestown Exhibit. In addition to shipping orders are notations of payments/costs of shipping.
  - Shipping Orders and Payments (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Minutes of Committee Meetings (Box-folder 1:2)
- Correspondence 1907
  This series contains letters written mostly to Rev. E. P. Minor, the Secretary of the Committee of the Jamestown Exposition. Other letters are addressed to various members of churches across the state of Virginia regarding their involvement in the creation of the exhibit. The correspondence deals with finding photographs, documents, paintings, and other artifacts to include in the exhibit; Mr. and Mrs. P. Yeatman's correspondence concerning the welfare of the exhibit and its maintenance. responses from college ministries; letters to A.R. Goodwin; letters written by Reverend C.B. Bryan about the items being shipped, ways to keep up the display, and offering help to other committee members; a letter written by Reverend Alfred Magill Randolph, the Chairman of the Committee on Arrangements for the Jamestown Exhibit, discussing the impact of the First Episcopalian Church on this region and comments on some of the items that could be found within the Jamestown Exhibit of 1907.
  - Letters to E. P. Minor: January/February (I) January/February 1907 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Letters to E. P. Minor March/April 1907 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Letters to E. P. Minor May/June 1907 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Letters to E. P. Minor July/August 1907 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Letters to E. P. Minor September/October (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Letters to E. P. Minor November/December 1907 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Letters to E. P. Minor January 1908 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Letters to E. P. Minor: Postcards (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Letter by Reverend A. F. Randolph (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Letters by Reverend C. B. Bryan (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Letters from Members of Other Churches (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (I) - Yeatman (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (II) (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Committee Stationary/Letterheads (Box-folder 1:16)